Guide to the Daggett Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Daggett family papers
1755-1859
MS 1382
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The papers include correspondence, sermons, and legal and financial papers of Alfred, Ebenezeer, Henry (1741-1830), Henry (1758-1843), Horace, Naphtali, and William Daggett. Naphtali Daggett was president of Yale College from 1766 to 1777. Deeds (quit claims) of William Daggett form the bulk of the collection.
Daggett family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gifts from various sources, 1931-1975, and purchases from several dealers, 1944-1954.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Additional Henry Daggett (1741-1830) material is available in the Hooker Family Papers (MS 289). Additional Naphtali Daggett material is available in the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
Scope and Contents
The Daggett Family papers include correspondence, sermons, and legal and financial papers of Daggett family members: Alfred, Ebenezer, Henry (1741-1830), Henry (1758-1843), Horace, Naphtali, and William Daggett. Napthali, who was president of Yale College (1766-1777), and Henry (1758-1843) were father and son; the relationships of other family members is distant or unclear.
Alfred Daggett is represented by 1845 orders from the probate court to him as executor to the estate of Ezra Daggett (folder 5). For Ebenezer Daggett there is an inventory of his estate (folder 1) following his death while serving in the Second Connecticut Regiment. This document was purchased from Hurwitz in 1945. A letter of Henry Daggett's (1741-1830) to his wife while he was serving in the Connecticut State Legislature and a portrait are also in folder 1. These were donated to the library by Mrs. Henry Daggett Hooker in 1931. Similar material is included in the Hooker Family papers (MS 289). Some papers of Henry Daggett (1758-1843) as justice of the peace are in folder 4; these were the gift of Robert J. Barry in 1948. A few legal papers of Horace Daggett from Mobile, Alabama are in folder 5.
There is a deed to Maphtali Daggett in folder 4 for property in Smithtown, Long Island, while folder 2 contains a letter and manuscript and printed sermons. Mrs. F. Allen Sherk donated (1975) the sermons, which include one on the death of Yale President Thomas Clap and another given in the college chapel. The letter, written while Naphtali Daggett was serving as president of Yale, was purchased from Goodspeed's in 1954. Many additional letters and sermons of Naphtali Daggett are housed in the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
William Daggett is represented by the largest quantity of material in the papers. Folder 4 and 5 contain approximately fifty deeds, quit claims, and building contracts for property in New Haven. These materials were purchased from M. Earle in 1944.
Connecticut; Deeds; Sermons; Clergy; Daggett, Ebenezer, d. 1781; Daggett, Henry, 1741-1830; Daggett, Henry, 1758-1843; Daggett, Naphtali, 1727-1780; Daggett, William; Doggett family; Yale University -- Religion
- Inventory
  - Daggett, Ebenezer
    - Estate inventory, 1781 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daggett, Henry
    - ALS to Elizabeth Daggett, 1783 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Photograph of portrait, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daggett, Naphtali
    - ALS to Eleazar Wheelock, 1769 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Biographical notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sermons, 1758, 1767, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financial and legal papers, 1755, 1819-1859, undated (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Oversize
    - Princeton and Harvard degrees of Naphtali Daggett, 1774, 1777 (Box 2)